{
    "1": {
      "type": "MCQ",
      "question": "Which pandas function is used to read a CSV file?",
      "option1": "read_csv()",
      "option2": "read_xlsx()",
      "option3": "read()",
      "option4": "csv_read()",
      "answer": "read_csv()"
    },
    "2": {
      "type": "MCQ",
      "question": "How do you set the DataFrame index as 'date'?",
      "option1": "df.set_index('date')",
      "option2": "df['date'].set_index()",
      "option3": "df.index('date')",
      "option4": "df['date'] = index",
      "answer": "df.set_index('date')"
    },
    "3": {
      "type": "MCQ",
      "question": "What is used to handle missing data in pandas?",
      "option1": "dropna()",
      "option2": "fillna()",
      "option3": "Both dropna() and fillna()",
      "option4": "drop_fill()",
      "answer": "Both dropna() and fillna()"
    },
    "4": {
      "type": "MCQ",
      "question": "Which operation changes the DataFrame, but does not change the memory address of the DataFrame?",
      "option1": "Shallow operations",
      "option2": "Deep operations",
      "option3": "Both of them",
      "option4": "None of them",
      "answer": "Shallow operations"
    },
    "5": {
      "type": "MCQ",
      "question": "How to replace all null values in a DataFrame?",
      "option1": "fillna(value)",
      "option2": "replaceNull(value)",
      "option3": "replace_na(value)",
      "option4": "dropna(value)",
      "answer": "fillna(value)"
    },
    "6": {
      "type": "Theory",
      "question": "What is Pandas in Python?",
      "answer": "Pandas is a software library written for the Python programming language for data manipulation and analysis. In particular, it offers data structures and operations for manipulating numerical tables and time series."
    },
    "7": {
      "type": "Theory",
      "question": "What is a DataFrame in Pandas?",
      "answer": "In Pandas, a Dataframe is a two-dimensional size-mutable, potentially heterogeneous tabular data structure with labeled axes (rows and columns)."
    },
    "8": {
      "type": "Theory",
      "question": "What is the purpose of pandas in Python?",
      "answer": "Pandas is used for data manipulation, analysis and cleaning. It provides special data structures which are able to perform operations on both numerical data and time-series."
    },
    "9": {
      "type": "Coding",
      "question": "Write a Python code to create a pandas Series from a dictionary.",
      "answer": "Here is the Python code:\nimport pandas as pd\ndata = {'a' : 0., 'b' : 1., 'c' : 2.}\ns = pd.Series(data)\nprint(s)"
    },
    "10": {
      "type": "Coding",
      "question": "Write a Python code to change the data type of a pandas DataFrame column.",
      "answer": "Here is the Python code:\ndf['column name'] = df['column name'].astype('data type')"
    }
  }
